Let somebody say: "Thank you, Jesus!"
Indeed, a million thanks are not enough to express our gratitude to God
for what you have been seeing from the beginning of the service.
Let somebody say: "The Lord is here". Let somebody say: "The Healer is in our midst."
Let somebody say: "The living God is in our midst."
The Creator of Heaven and earth is in our midst through his Word and by his Spirit
Give thanks to Him.
Say: "Lord Jesus, I thank you for every moment of Your attention".
Say: "Lord, we don't know how to satisfy the needs of our lives
but Lord, You do - that's why I'm here."
Say: "Lord, that's why I'm here."
Give thanks to God for His mercy and for His grace.
You maybe seated in His presence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
Am I talking to believers?
I hear only two.
Am I talking to believers in Christ?
If I am talking to a genuine believer, a smile should enlighten your face
because you know it has been done already.
Yes, brethren.
Christianity is not a religion but a living relationship with a living God.
Just because a person calls himself a Christian does not mean he is a believer.
A man of sense-knowledge belief may mentally assent and never have;
he may hope and never have.
He may be familiar with the original text of the of the Scriptures in Greek and Hebrew,
he may know the history of the Word and still never have.
Let someone say:
It is not our logic, our philosophy, our knowledge that brings about a new life in Christ Jesus.
Men may mentally assent and not have.
Men may do much by outward restraint but lack the character of God in their resolutions.
That's why the Bible says in the Book of Matthew 7:20
By their fruit you shall know them.
Jesus Christ never strived to look good; He was simply good.
Jesus Christ never strived to have a good reputation; He had character from above.
A man can be a Christian by profession, by confession and not such in heart.
Human knowledge, human understanding oftentimes makes a mistaken judgement
of character but the Lord only values the holy faith, love, peace - the fruit of the spirit -
embedded in your heart, beyond human discernment
This leads us to the title of our message:
CHRISTIANITY IS ALL ABOUT HEART
Let's somebody say: "True Christianity is all about heart."
Let me take you to the book of Matthew 15:8
It says,
"These people draw near to Me with their mouth and honour me with their lips,
but their heart is far from me..."
Verse 9:
"And in vain they worship Me, teaching as doctrines the commandments of men."
Let somebody say: "It's all about heart."
The Book of Proverbs 27:19 says that
our life reflects what is in our hearts.
This means the heart refers to the man himself.
The Prophet T.B. Joshua says
it is the seat of desires, emotions, knowledge, conscience and moral character.
Let somebody say: "Living is all about heart."
2 Corinthians 5.
The mind of God says that if anyone is in Christ Jesus, he is a new creation.
The old man has ceased to be; the new man has taken place.
This means your past is over. Say: "My past is over."
When your past is over, it means you are born anew.
It means you are sanctified by the truth of Christ.
When you give the control of your life to Jesus, the Lord will give you a new heart,
He will give you a new nature and new desire to please Him.
Say: "Neighbour,
when you give the control of your life to God, He will give you a new heart,
a new desire to please Him."
Accepting Jesus Christ is to accept the nature of God.
How do we have the nature of God? It is God's Word that builds the nature of God into us.
In other words,
Christ is building Himself into us, as His Word rules, dominates and sanctifies our spirit nature.
Let somebody say:
"God's Word is spirit and life."
Whatever my heart engages on, influences my conduct and my character.
The Holy Spirit uses God's Word to act upon our soul to produce the virtues of Christ's character.
God's Word can only enlighten you and me, it can only quicken us
when it is illumined by the Spirit of God.
God's Word reflects His character.
When the Word of God dominates our mouth, it will dominate our heart.
When the Word of God dominates our heart, it will influence our behaviour, our character, our attitude.
Let someone say:
"The Word of God - the living Word -
the Word of God is the living presence of the divine power.
It is God's power working through His Word and by His Spirit that brings about a new life.
I am here for a change. My life will change. My attitude will change. My past is over.
The evidence of Christ Jesus is lives changed.
Today, if you believe, no matter your past,
Jesus has come to put an end to your past and give birth to your future.
The Gospel of God's grace challenges and changes everything.
We have seen a sinner's character being healed.
We have seen a liar becoming truthful.
We have seen a drunkard becoming sober.
To His power nothing is impossible.
Saul grew up under the feet of Gameliel. He knew all the rights of the law of Moses.
But the Bible says he was serving a God he did not know.
Because we can't God by outward things.
He was persecuting those who believed in Christ Jesus.
Because he was living outside the truth, where the true light comes from.
Saul simply needed to know God better.
Say: "Neighbour,
you need to know God better. No matter your problem, focus on God.
You need to know God better." Just an encounter with the Lord and your life will change today.
After his encounter with Jesus,
Saul's sense-knowledge belief gave way to a new kind of knowledge.
It is a spiritual knowledge, revelation knowledge.
The Bible says that
immediately Saul discovered the man God wanted him to be, the great Apostle Paul.
Jesus Christ never disconnects Himself from anyone who makes mistakes in their life.
No matter what brought you here today, no matter the mistakes you have committed -
there is hope for you.
I say, there is hope for you.
Jesus never rejected anyone who came to Him for healing, deliverance, salvation.
There was a woman of bad character.
The Bible says she was a sinful woman.
But she met Jesus in the house of Simon, the Pharisee.
Jesus met her in the condition where she was rejected because of the sinful life she was living.
But immediately she knew about Jesus, the Bible says, she became conscious of her sins
and she ran to Jesus ready to restore and make peace with her Creator, Jesus Christ the Lord.
She came to Jesus behind, crying and Jesus saw in her an attitude of remorse, humility,
self-denial and a desire to change.
And the Lord was moved to compassion, brushed aside her unworthy past
and her life of prostitution came to an end.
She became a woman of noble character.
I want you to talk to your neighbour, say: "Neighbour,
I don't know what you are going through,
I don't know where you are coming from,
I don't know what your challenge is
but all I know, we are are serving a God who never dodges crisis.
He sees them as a challenge.
If you put your problem into the hand of Jesus today, He will put his peace in your heart.
Say neighbour: "Are you such in heart?"
Ask your neighbour: "Are you such in heart?"
Man of God says:
"The principal source of finding ourselves spiritually, the principal source of knowing ourselves saved
is the Holy Bible; there is no substitute to it.
The Word of God is the seed of divine life that comes into our heart and causes faith to grow.
And faith purifies the heart and sanctifies it from all those lusts of the world.
Are you ready?
Say: "Neighbour, are you ready?
For the radical transformation
that only God can bring?
Today, many confess the name of Jesus Christ and deny Him in action.
Many confess the name of the Lord and deny Him by their attitude.
Their attitude does not reflect what they believe. What is the cause of this?
Only our character can testify to our confession of Jesus.
Jesus Christ has no place in the heart not dominated by His Word.
The word has priority over His name.
We must be grounded, rooted in the Word of God before we call that name,
before we bring Jesus on the scene.
Failure to give Jesus Christ His proper position in our hearts is actually responsible
for the crisis of our faith today.
Let someone say:
"Failure to give Jesus His proper position in our heart is actually responsible
for the crisis of our faith.
In other words, failure to allow the Word of God in the midst of our hearts
is actually responsible for the crisis of our faith.
Brethren, I put to you finally.
In Christ Jesus there is a general offer of life and salvation to all who believe.
When you accept Jesus Christ genuinely,
you have the very presence of God in your heart through the Holy Spirit.
And the man of God says
the Holy Spirit is God's imperative of life. He is a Giver of all life.
He renews and changes our lives.
The basic work of the Spirit of God in our life in salvation is to impart a new life
into the heart of the believer.
Thus making me and you a child of God, a true believer in Christ.
I want you to stand up in His presence. Say:
"Lord Jesus, I am here for a change.
I am here, Lord, for the radical transformation of my life that only You can bring.
Lord, here I am. I believe; help me overcome my unbelief.
Here I am.
In the mighty name of Jesus Christ."
Brethren,
the moment you make Jesus the CEO, the Director of your life,
you will be wired to the creator in a unique way.
You will fear no more; you will worry no more.
I am reconciled; I am linked up with God.
Brethren,
to be born again is to have a new life.
Repentance is our only hope for God's mercy.
It is a commitment to a new way of life.
It is a commitment to a new way of righteousness of following God in Spirit and in truth.
When you follow Jesus today, your life will change, your attitude will change
and you will become saved and delivered in Jesus' name.
May the Word of God bless your heart in Jesus Christ's name.
Thank you, Jesus.
TT Monica Asefa 01/04/19
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 05/04/2019